ANDRÉS SOLÍS MONTERO

Updated: February 19, 2018

www.solism.ca · ☎ (613) 265-4482 · ☑ andres@solism.ca
 212-171 O'Connor St · Ottawa ON · Canada K2P1T4

OVERVIEW

Software Developer

Over 15 years of experience in software and web development. Particularly interested in Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Object Oriented Programming languages, Data Structures and Algorithms, and scripting solutions. Developer who enjoys simplicity in design, creative code, innovation, with a kind eye for designing and developing Graphical User Interfaces. Encourages collaborative work environments, stimulates group creativity and promotes sharing of knowledge. Experienced in C++, Python, Java, Web technologies, and SQL databases.

Research scientist

Strong background in Computer Vision, Image Processing, Machine and Deep Learning solutions applied to shape analysis, object detection, tracking, people re-identification and metric learning applications. Published over 10 publications with 500+ citation, and technical reviewer for 8+ years.

Teaching experience

Teaching computer science, programming languages, and advance programming concepts for over 10 years. Has taught over 10 courses.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2016-Present

Co-Founder, Research & Development, Software Engineer

Tempo Analytics, Canada Architect, team technical lead, and full stack software developer of a server-client application to deliver speed of service time statistics for the Quick Service Industry. Creating deep learning and computer vision solutions for customer detection, people re-identification, and metric learning. Designing and developing web tools to control the application's nodes and display the customer analytics.

Reference: Robert Johnsen \cdot +1 (201) 424-6374 \cdot robertj@tempo-analytics.com **Reference**: Prof. Robert Laganière \cdot +1 (613) 562-5800x6707 \cdot robert@laganiere.name

2010–2016

Research Assistant, Computer Vision Software Developer

University of Ottawa, Canada

Responsible for writing research papers, presenting research findings, and develop computer vision and machine learning software to test and validate the results. Research on shape analysis, object detection and tracking solutions for augmented reality, robot localization, and surveillance applications.

Reference: Prof. Jochen Lang \cdot +1 (613) 562-5800x6317 \cdot jlang@eecs.uottawa.ca **Reference**: Prof. Robert Laganière \cdot +1 (613) 562-5800x6707 \cdot robert@laganiere.name

2011–2012 Proximify

Senior Web Developer

Design and development of the javascript template engine powering UniWeb and CCV Sync. A web-based software for academic institutions and grant agencies, a research network builder and a tool for creating and maintenance of your Canadian Common CVs.

Reference: PhD. Diego Macrini +1 (613) 828 6274 · macrini@proximify.ca

Web Developer 2010–2011

Dalen Design Development and maintenance of the e-commerce website: Hot Tub Covers Canada.

Processing electronic payments, showcasing products, accessories, descriptions, managing

reviews and comments.

Reference: Jessica Dalen +1 (613) 421 2686 · jessica@dalendesign.ca

2009-2010 **Software Developer**

Hegyi Geomatics international Inc

Design and development of tools for the forest industry. Image analysis of forest stands

using high resolution and Landsat imagery (Java, and C++).

Reference: MSc. Frank Hegyi +1 (613) 526 9967 · fhegyi@hegyigeomatics.com

Research Assistant, Computer Vision Software Developer 2008-2010

University of Ottawa, Canada

Responsible for writing research papers, presenting research findings, and develop computer vision software to test and validate the results. Research on image processing

techniques to extract relevant features from images.

Reference: Prof. Amiya Nayak · +1 (613) 562 5800x2165 · anayak@eecs.uottawa.ca

2006-2008 **Software Developer**

Navaera USA LLC

Creating a web crawler and multi-platform tools for automatic clustering of documents

from the web based on their content and metadata (Java, C#, and Python). Reference: Matthew Adler · madler@navaera.com

Network Administrator, Software Developer 2006-2008

University of Havana, Cuba

IT Team leader for the main building of the University of Havana. Design, development, and validation of network administration tools for user monitoring, domain login, email access, and internet quota management. Provide network support and IT services.

Reference: Sofia Sanjuán Gómez · +53 (7) 873 0123 · sanjuan@rect.uh.cu

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science GPA: 10.0/10.0 2010-2016

University of Ottawa, Canada

Thesis: Efficient Feature extraction for Shape Analysis, Object Detection and Tracking Robust feature representations to aid shape analysis, object detection and tracking.

Supervisors: Prof. Jochen Lang & Prof. Robert Laganière

Master of Computer Science GPA: 10.0/10.0 2009-2010

University of Ottawa, Canada

Thesis: Towards Feature Detection based on Morphology of Objects on Images Extracting lines and corners from images based on the morphology of objects.

Supervisor: Prof. Amiya Nayak

2001-2006 **Bachelor of Computer Science** GPA: 4.56/5.0 (magna cum laude)

University of Thesis: Diskless Cluster: Parallel and Distributed Systems Havana, Cuba

Bootable Cluster LiveCD based on Debian GNU/Linux distribution.

Supervisor: Prof. Joel de la Noval

PUBLICATIONS

- 2016 Matej Kristan, Andrés Solís Montero et al. The Visual Object Tracking VOT2016 Challenge Results. The European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, Springer, 2016.
- 2016 Matej Kristan, Andrés Solís Montero et al. The Thermal Infrared Visual Object Tracking VOT-TIR2016 Challenge Results. The European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, Springer, 2016.
- 2015 Andrés Solís Montero, Jochen Lang, Robert Laganire. Scalable Kernel Correlation Filter With Sparse Feature Integration. The IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV 2015), VOT Challenge, pages 24-31, Dec. 2015.
- 2015 Matej Kristan, Andrés Solís Montero et al. The Visual Object Tracking VOT2015 Challenge Results. The IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) Workshops, pages 1-23, Dec. 2015.
- 2015 Michael Felsberg, Andrés Solís Montero et al. The Thermal Infrared Visual Object Tracking VOT-TIR2015 Challenge Results. The IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) Workshops, pages 76-88, Dec. 2015.
- 2015 Andrés Solís Montero, Jochen Lang, Robert Laganire. A General Framework for Fast 3D Object Detection and Localization Using an Uncalibrated Camera. IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV 2015), pages 884-891, Jan. 2015.
- 2012 Andrés Solís Montero, Hicham Sekkati, Jochen Lang, Robert Laganire, Jeremy James. Framework for Natural Landmark-based Robot Localization. Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Computer and Robot Vision (CRV), pages 131-138, April 2012.
- 2012 Andrés Solís Montero, Jochen Lang. Skeleton pruning by contour approximation and the integer medial axis transform. *Computers & Graphics*, 36(5), pages 477-487, March 2012.
- 2010 Milos Stojmenovic, Andres Solis Montero, Amiya Nayak. Colour and texture based pyramidal image segmentation. *IEEE International Conference on Audio Language and Image Processing (ICALIP)*, pages 778-786, Nov. 2010.
- 2010 Andres Solis Montero, Milos Stojmenovic, Amiya Nayak. Robust detection of corners and corner-line links in images. *IEEE 10th International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (CIT)*, pages 495-502, Jun. 2010.
- 2010 Milos Stojmenovic, Andres Solis Montero, Amiya Nayak. Co-parent selection for fast region merging in pyramidal image segmentation. IEEE 2nd International Conference on Image Processing Theory Tools and Applications (IPTA), pages 243-248, July 2010.
- 2009 Andres Solis Montero, Amiya Nayak, Milos Stojmenovic, Nejib Zaguia. Robust Line Extraction Based on Repeated Segment Directions on Image Contours. IEEE Symposium: Computational Intelligence for Security and Defence Applications (CISDA), pages 1-7, July 2009.
- 2009 Milos Stojmenovic, Andres Solis Montero, Amiya Nayak. Link Shifting Based Pyramid Segmentation for Elongated Regions. Signal Processing, Image Processing and Pattern Recognition, Springer Berlin Heidelberg, pages 141-152, 2009.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2009 – 2015	Teaching	Assistant:
-------------	----------	------------

University of Programming Paradigms. (CSI2120). Winter $20\{15 \mid 11\}$. Ottawa

> Operative Systems (CSI 3131), Summer 2015.

> Advanced Programming Concepts in $C++\{11\}$ (CSI 2372). Fall 20{14 | 12 | 10}.

> Introduction to Computing I & (ITI 11{20 | 21} - Python), Fall 2015.

> Introduction to Computing I & II (ITI 11{20 | 21} - Java), Winter $20\{14 \mid 13\}$.

> Computing Concepts for Business (CSI1306). Fall 2009.

Network Administration in GNU/Linux, 2006 - 2008

Fall 20{7 | 8}

University of Object Oriented Programming with Java and C#, Summer $20\{8 \mid 7\}$. Havana

> SQL and Relational Database Model Concepts, Fall 2005

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Computer Vision · Image Processing · Machine Learning Data Structure & Algorithms · Expertise Object-Oriented Programming · RDMS (i.e., MSQL, MySQL, Postgres, and SQLite) · Networking · Web Development/Design · e-Commerce · GIS · MVC

Markup and $C++\cdot C\cdot C\#\cdot Java\cdot PHP\cdot Python\cdot Matlab\cdot JavaScript\cdot Prolog\cdot Perl\cdot Bash\cdot$ Programming JavaScript · Haskel · HTML 5 · XML · CSS 3

Languages

Software Development Tools

OpenCV · Eclipse · Visual Studio · Xcode · Git · SVN · make · ¡Query · LATEX · Adobe Photoshop · Adobe Illustrator · Adobe Dreamweaver · OpenOffice · Microsoft Office Tools

HONORS & AWARDS

- 2016 NSERC Engage Grant Program with Ross Video.
- 2015 Best real-time tracking method VOT Challenge 2015, Chile
- NSERC Engage Grant Program with Thales Canada. 2015
- 2014 NSERC Engage Grant Program with You.i labs.
- 2012 NSERC Engage Grant Program with Cohort Systems Inc.
- NSERC CRD Grant with Pulse Microsystems Ltd. 2011
- 2010 International Admission Scholarship from University of Ottawa.
- Ontario Centres of Excellence Grant with Hegyi Geomatics International Inc. 2010 Project: Green Earth (GIS).
- Excellence Scholarship from University of Ottawa. 2009
- 2009 Ontario Centres of Excellence Grant with Hegyi Geomatics International Inc. Project: Green Earth (GIS).
- 2009 MITACS Accelerate Internship Program for graduate and postdoctoral fellows. Project: Advanced Tools for Forest Inventory and Management.

2006 Magma cum laude graduate as Bachelor in Computer Science

2004 Creator of "linUHx" GNU/Linux distribution adopted by three Cuban Universities: University of Havana, CUJAE, and UCI.

2004 2nd position at 10th International Convention "Informática 2004, Cuba." Project: Electronic Magazine "E-zines".

TECHNICAL REVIEWS - JOURNALS AND CONFERENCES

IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation & Measurement. TIM 20{16 | 17 | 18}.

IEEE Transactions on Image Processing. TIP 2015.

IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo. ICME 2013.

IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation. ICRA 2013.

IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo. ICME 2012.

IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo. ICME 2011.

7th IEEE International Conference on Mobile Ad-hoc and Sensor Systems. MASS 2010.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages English: Full professional proficiency

SPANISH: Mothertongue

Affiliations ACM member · IEEE member · International High IQ Society member

Interests & Motorcycle Riding · Dancing · Music · Soccer · Volleyball · Skating · Baseball

Hobbies · Cross-country skiing · Discovering new places and restaurants